<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes" ?>
<content>
	<pagetitle>Style guides for my nicknames</pagetitle>
	<textheader>"rantanplan"</textheader>
	<text>
		<rimg href="?document=images/rantanplan.jpg" title="rantanplan" /> 
		<noop>This is the style guide for my IRC nickname "rantanplan" @ irc.german-elite.net. This style guide has been inspired by </noop>
		<namedlink href="http://www252.pair.com/comdog/style.html">brian d foy's</namedlink>
		<noop> style guide. This style guide helps you to write my nickname in the correct way!</noop>
    </text>
	<textsubheader>The rules</textsubheader>
	<text>
		<noop>The following rules have to be met:</noop>
		<enumeration>
			<enumitem>Each letter in rantanplan must be of the same case. Lower case is preferred. Any capitalization is incorrect unless each letter is capitalized.</enumitem>
			<enumitem>Sentences should not start with rantanplan if you normally capitalize the first word of a sentence. Recast the sentence so that it begins with a capital letter. Or just write the whole sentence in small or capitalized letters!</enumitem>
			<enumitem>If rantanplan is too long for you, you may use rant or ranti instead.</enumitem>
			<enumitem>If you like rantanplan very much, you may use rantiplanti as his nickname!</enumitem>
			<enumitem>Sometimes rantanplan changes his nick into some weird combinations like plantanran or ranplantan or tanplanrantanplan! Any version is valid! You can think of 3 main body parts: ran tan and plan. You may combine them in any order!</noop>
			<enumitem>The above mentioned is also valid for the reversed body parts: nar nat nalp. This combination is valid as well: nartanranplannat.</menuitem>
			<enumitem>Sometimes rantanplan likes to show other people on what cool stuff he is working on. In this case a |foo postfix is added to any version of his nickname. E.g.: ranti|C means, that rantanplan is currently coding in C. rantanplan|vs|work means, that he is fighting against his current task at work!</enumitem>
			<enumitem>Another way to express what rantanplan is doing is a prefix notation like worktanplan (he is working) or eattanplan (he is eating).</enumitem>
		</enumeration>
	</text>
	<textheader>"pbuetow"</textheader>
	<text>
		<noop>This is the style guide for my nickname "pbuetow".</bnoop>
    </text>
	<textsubheader>The rules</textsubheader>
	<text>
		<noop>The following rules have to be met:</noop>
		<enumeration>
			<enumitem>Each letter in pbuetow must be of the same case. Any capitalization is incorrect. Except if all letters are uppercase! "pbuetow" and "PBUETOW" are the only correct ways to spell this nick! All other versions are invalid!</enumitem>
			<enumitem>I may also use buetow instead of pbuetow (like on PerlMonks)! pcbuetow may be used, if pbuetow and/or buetow is taken.</enumitem>
		</enumeration>
	</text>
</content>
